<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid url="http://dlib.nyu.edu/findingaids/html/tamwag/tam_590">tam_590</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper>Guide to the Richard W. Franke Files on Indonesia and East Timor <num>TAM.590</num></titleproper><author>Makoroba Sow</author></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives</publisher><address><addressline>Elmer Holmes Bobst Library</addressline><addressline>70 Washington Square South</addressline><addressline>2nd Floor</addressline><addressline>New York, NY 10012</addressline><addressline>special.collections@nyu.edu</addressline><addressline>URL: <extptr xlink:href="http://library.nyu.edu/about/collections/special-collections-and-archives/special-collections/" xlink:show="new" xlink:title="http://library.nyu.edu/about/collections/special-collections-and-archives/special-collections/" xlink:type="simple"/></addressline></address></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2021-01-21 15:54:15 -0500</date>.</creation><langusage>Finding aid is written in English</langusage><descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules></profiledesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">
  <did>
    <repository>
      <corpname>Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>Richard W. Franke Files on Indonesia and East Timor</unittitle>
    <origination label="Creator">
      <persname source="naf">Franke, Richard W.</persname>
    </origination>
    <unitid>TAM.590</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="part">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">13 Linear Feet</extent>
      <extent altrender="carrier">in 22 legal manuscript boxes, 1 flat box, and 1 flat file.</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <physdesc altrender="part">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">1 film reels</extent>
      <extent altrender="carrier">in 1 flat box.</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <physdesc altrender="part">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">1 audiocassette</extent>
      <extent altrender="carrier">in 1 Shared Cassette Box.</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate normal="1961/1993" type="inclusive">circa 1961-1993</unitdate>
    <abstract id="aspace_4c9a266e0e19332219c3d289c6c85daf">Dr. Richard W. Franke is Professor Emeritus of Anthropology at Montclair State University. Franke served on the board of the now defunct U.S. branch of TAPOL, a UK-based advocacy organization initially formed in 1973 to support political prisoners in Indonesia. This collection contains Dr. Franke's research material related to the Indonesian occupation of East Timor, the East Timor genocide, and Indonesian political prisoners. The collection consists of correspondence, publications, reports, articles, clippings, manuscripts, and a small grouping of photographs, other print material and memorabilia.</abstract>
    <physloc id="aspace_8723e3101249be213c9a69a4ed976b33">Materials are stored offsite and advance notice is required for use. Please request materials at least two business days prior to your research visit to coordinate access.</physloc>
    <langmaterial id="aspace_ecae9a7c40a83ee2ae4185d1af2181d0">The majority of materials are in English, with some  materials in Indonesian, French, Dutch, Portuguese, and other languages.</langmaterial>
  </did>
  <accessrestrict id="aspace_839272d568d513d9078519e6113091b0">
    <head>Conditions Governing Access</head>
<p>Materials are open without restrictions.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <acqinfo id="aspace_2f8ab92cb8b8b4825435f1ecd6010482">
    <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head>
<p>The materials were found in collection and the provenance is unknown. The accession number associated with this collection is 2011.118.</p>  </acqinfo>
  <arrangement id="aspace_eec67b5bf73051251bdf769b862b7b49">
    <head>Arrangement</head>
<p>Materials from each series, with the exception of the photographic materials, were physically grouped together with little further arrangement. Oversize materials and audio visual materials were separated out and appropriately housed.</p><p>The collection is organized into eight series: I. Publications and Reports; II. Subject Files; III. Articles and Clippings; IV. Correspondence; V. Franke's Writings; VI. Photographic Materials; VII. Graphic Materials and Memorabilia; VIII. Unprocessed Audiovisual Materials.</p>  </arrangement>
  <bioghist id="aspace_3049fdef0b7984dfef5d34fb92c849b6">
    <head>Biographical Note</head>
<p>Dr. Richard W. Franke is Professor Emeritus of Anthropology at Montclair State University, after serving on the faculty from 1972 to 2009. Franke wrote and advocated extensively on the Indonesian occupation of East Timor. Franke also served on the board of the now defunct U.S. branch of TAPOL (located in Montclair, NJ), a UK-based advocacy organization initially formed in 1973 to support political prisoners in Indonesia. Their mission later expanded to encompass general human rights concerns in Indonesia and East Timor. Franke edited the U.S. <emph render="italic">Tapol Bulletin</emph>, the official publication of TAPOL USA, from 1975 until 1980.</p>  </bioghist>
  <prefercite id="aspace_cada0446cef3a17ae6bd7985721e78f4">
    <head>Preferred Citation</head>
<p>Identification of item, date; Richard W. Franke Files on Indonesia and East Timor; TAM 590; box number; folder number; Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives, New York University.</p>  </prefercite>
  <processinfo id="aspace_82dc016a8f165d047b11892322308db0">
    <head>Processing Information</head>
<p>The collection was inventoried by Rachel Ann Schimke and Daniel Michelson in September 2011.  Periodicals and books were separated for cataloging.  Some routine financial information was discarded.</p><p>The collection was processed by Makoroba Sow in October 2019. Folder titles for materials in Series II. Subject Files were mostly retained from original folder titles, with clarifying description in brackets.</p>  </processinfo>
  <relatedmaterial id="aspace_dc671ea60851b33042991592bf687908">
    <head>Related Material at the Tamiment Library/Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives</head>
<p>East Timor and Indonesia Action Network (ETAN) Records (TAM 393)</p>  </relatedmaterial>
  <scopecontent id="aspace_61a718a440f0a554635bcc903e2cf445">
    <head>Scope and Contents</head>
<p>The Richard W. Franke Files on Indonesia and East Timor contains research material dating from 1961-1991 related to Indonesia's genocidal occupation of East Timor, which lasted from 1975 to 1999. The bulk of the collection is dated 1975-1980 and consists of articles and clippings from U.S and international news media, and publications and reports from human rights and advocacy organizations. The articles and clippings reflect the news coverage of the Indonesian occupation and other writings on the history, politics, and culture of Indonesia, East Timor, and other Asian and Pacific Island nations. The publications and reports, as well as the subject files, and correspondence, details the advocacy work of organizations such as TAPOL USA and UK, East Timor Defense Committee, and Amnesty International. Many of the organizations are US, UK, and Australia based. Much of the correspondence reflects Franke's work with TAPOL and other activist or advocacy groups. The collection also contains a substantial number UN and US. Congressional records, predominantly statements and testimonies. A small number of materials reflect liberation struggles of Western Sahara, Asian and Pacific Island nations and peoples. There is a small number of photographic and graphic materials, and memorabilia related to the work and causes of TAPOL and other political and human rights groups.</p>  </scopecontent>
  <phystech id="aspace_ee18446bfc9b4d78e8e3fdfbcfdb132b">
    <head>Audiovisual Access Policies and Procedures</head>
<p>Audiovisual materials have not been preserved and may not be available to researchers. Materials not yet digitized will need to have access copies made before they can be used. To request an access copy, or if you are unsure if an item has been digitized, please contact tamiment.wagner@nyu.edu, (212) 998-2630 with the collection name, collection number, and a description of the item(s) requested. A staff member will respond to you with further information.</p>  </phystech>
  <separatedmaterial id="aspace_71ab4916e12532357d132d826da34a84">
    <head>Separated Materials</head>
<p>In September 2011, approximately one hundred issues of the <emph render="italic">Tapol Bulletin</emph> (UK), <emph render="italic">Tapol Bulletin</emph> (US), <emph render="italic">Southeast Asian Chronicle</emph>, <emph render="italic">Indonesia: feiten en meningen</emph>, and the <emph render="italic">East Timor Estafeta</emph> were separated for cataloging, as were a couple dozen books.</p>  </separatedmaterial>
  <userestrict id="aspace_d817e3d93a468eaadffb5707c3d550ff">
    <head>Conditions Governing Use</head>
<p>Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archive has no information about copyright ownership for this collection and is not authorized to grant permission to publish or reproduce materials from it. Materials in this collection, which were created in circa 1960-circa 1990, are expected to enter the public domain in 2110.</p>  </userestrict>
  <appraisal id="aspace_2dcb92ee2cd015a9780f89ea4ddda5f2">
    <head>Appraisal</head>
<p>A small number of financial records were deaccessioned in 2019.</p>  </appraisal>
  <controlaccess>
    <geogname source="lcsh">Indonesia -- History -- 1966-1998.</geogname>
    <geogname source="lcsh">Timor-Leste -- History -- Autonomy and independence movements.</geogname>
    <subject source="lcsh">Human rights -- Indonesia.</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Human rights -- Timor-Leste.</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Political prisoners.</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Autonomy and independence movements.</subject>
    <geogname source="lcsh">Southeast Asia -- Politics and government -- 1945-</geogname>
    <persname source="naf">Franke, Richard W.</persname>
    <corpname source="naf">Tapol (Organization)</corpname>
    <corpname source="naf">Tapol--USA (Organization)</corpname>
  </controlaccess>
  <dsc><c id="aspace_3dd14ef58d126dff57ae3502e7d27957" level="series"><did><unittitle>Series I. Publications and Reports</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1965-1991, bulk 1970-1979
</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="aspace_a6eec17ad4a32874d8c2e94648497213"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>This series contains publications and reports documenting the Indonesian occupation of East Timor, particularly Indonesian political prisoners and human rights violations committed against the East Timorese by the Indonesian military. These publications and reports were generated by human rights organizations, public interest and advocacy groups, international organizations, political agencies, and independent writers. Some of the organizations represented are: TAPOL (UK, US and Canada), Campaign for an Independent East Timor, East Timor Defense Committee, the East Timor News Agency, Pacific Studies Center, East Timor Research Project, Clergy and Laity Concerned, Amnesty International, and the United Nations. Much of the material produced by the smaller independent advocacy and information centers were produced with donated labor.</p><p>Most of the publications specifically relate information and news updates on Indonesia's repressive occupation of East Timor, the state of political prisoners, the Fretilin struggle against the Indonesian military, and U.S., Australia, and other western nations' international policies on Indonesia and East Timor. There is a small number of materials related to Sukarno and Suharto, the first and second presidents of Indonesia respectively.
TAPOL publications include newsletters and bulletins of TAPOL's UK, US and Canadian divisions. TAPOL often created background histories and chronologies of the Indonesian occupation, as well as collections of media coverage.</p><p>Other publications pertain to anti-colonial and anti-imperial resistance, including activist and advocacy campaigns against Indonesian oppression, protests and global solidarity actions and mobilization efforts, and liberation movements outside of Indonesia. A smaller number of publications pertain generally to Indonesia at large, its political and economic development with a small grouping related to the communist party PKI.
 
There are a small number of publications pertaining to Western Sahara and West Papua. The Western Sahara materials particularly relate to the on-going Moroccan occupation and its resistance.  Some of this material pertains specifically to or was created by the Polisario Front (Frente Polisario) a Western Saharan armed resistance movement against Moroccan occupation. Much of the material related to the Western Sahara are French language. The material on West Papua (Western New Guinea) pertain to the Indonesian occupation of that region and repression, particularly the violence against indigenous populations, and its resistance.</p><p>These series also contain a substantial collection of reports of hearings to the U.S. House Committee on International Relations and the Committee on Foreign Affairs, circa 1970's. These reports relate to the human rights violations in East Timor and other Asian and Pacific Island nations, and U.S. aid relief to East Timor. There are also reports on U.S. policy in neighboring countries or other nations.
This series contains mostly English language material, with some material written in Indonesian, Dutch, French, Portuguese and other languages.</p></scopecontent><c id="aspace_b654d099fbc101b7027ab3b94ae5664f" level="file"><did><unittitle>Publications and Reports</unittitle><unitdate normal="1965/1991" type="inclusive">1965-1991</unitdate><container altrender="Manuscript box - Legal" id="aspace_a20ff5da0e09862cd0160fd4f6b290af" label="Mixed Materials [31142062851897]" type="box">16</container><container id="aspace_c12c528e8a823b4d8b25f2b08c80d6fd" parent="aspace_a20ff5da0e09862cd0160fd4f6b290af" type="folder">1-6</container><container altrender="Manuscript box - Legal" id="aspace_5823f848f8a46c7fb0244a962acb74cc" label="Mixed Materials [31142062851905]" type="box">17</container><container id="aspace_b9e8efa678ac73372cef9f950ca93367" parent="aspace_5823f848f8a46c7fb0244a962acb74cc" type="folder">1-10</container><container altrender="Manuscript box - Legal" id="aspace_f6091de69b786b704e9a35158ea30f00" label="Mixed Materials [31142062851913]" type="box">18</container><container id="aspace_52728c686f367d078f983d9093c77185" parent="aspace_f6091de69b786b704e9a35158ea30f00" type="folder">1-8</container><container altrender="Manuscript box - Legal" id="aspace_1cd449bf3b86ccca255998adacd7f7e6" label="Mixed Materials [31142062851921]" type="box">19</container><container id="aspace_aac6a5de62236f202f74498d84600854" parent="aspace_1cd449bf3b86ccca255998adacd7f7e6" type="folder">1-7</container><container altrender="Manuscript box - Legal" id="aspace_3aa8eca076d2f6d7ed6edf0c56fa782f" label="Mixed Materials [31142062851939]" type="box">20</container><container id="aspace_7351ca60658b9775eadd422aeae47f00" parent="aspace_3aa8eca076d2f6d7ed6edf0c56fa782f" type="folder">1-8</container><container altrender="Manuscript box - Legal" id="aspace_9261fa773d9219932b44e4014d031b53" label="Mixed Materials [31142062851947]" type="box">21</container><container id="aspace_283e5d89dfbf17e637fab55df69aaa5f" parent="aspace_9261fa773d9219932b44e4014d031b53" type="folder">1-7</container><container altrender="Manuscript box - Legal" id="aspace_afeb71f2966f4faa340f132c4e96696f" label="Mixed Materials [31142062851954]" type="box">22</container><container id="aspace_ed4ede6ad82d4e9acfd298b8068903b6" parent="aspace_afeb71f2966f4faa340f132c4e96696f" type="folder">1-7</container><container altrender="Flat OS Box - 16" id="aspace_23cecca27b1cb7884c5127e8b1976117" label="Mixed Materials [31142062851962]" type="box">23</container><container id="aspace_03c96dbcae0cabfb0848b2a84349e120" parent="aspace_23cecca27b1cb7884c5127e8b1976117" type="folder">1-5</container></did></c></c><c id="aspace_f8aa330ba9bf8985dbac34420bba9904" level="series"><did><unittitle>Series II. Subject Files</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1968-1982, undated, bulk 1975-1980</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="aspace_74306585eb6750542d3755545e259a23"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>This series contains materials related to specific organizations, topics, or writers on East Timor and Indonesia. This series contains a significant number of TAPOL organizational material, correspondence, mailing lists, meeting minutes and notes.  It also includes groupings of news clippings of interest to TAPOL and its newsletters from the UK, Australia, Indonesia and other countries. 
 
Much of the series consists of press releases, reports, correspondence and other print material from organizations such as the Democratic Republic of East Timor, Fretilin, East Timor Defense Committee, Campaign for an Independent East Timor, the Committee to Protect Journalists, PEN International, and Amnesty International.  
 
There are also some files of writings by particular academic scholars related to the occupation of East Timor, Indonesia, and broader regional history, culture and politics. Of note is a file pertaining to Noam Chomsky's activism related to East Timor, including his correspondence with Franke.
 
Box 9 of this series contains a substantial grouping of statements, testimonies and speeches on East Timor - many of which were presented to the UN and the U.S. Congress.
 
Some of the material in the subject files can be found in Series I. and Series III.</p></scopecontent><c id="aspace_765491052caf26cfe495f834a9a07718" level="file"><did><unittitle>Subject Files</unittitle><unitdate normal="1968/1982" type="inclusive">1968-1982</unitdate><container altrender="Manuscript box - Legal" id="aspace_ad74f72219a3b4707f9495de86d0cdb3" label="Mixed Materials [31142063073574]" type="box">1</container><container id="aspace_5f6a74ffb85e9535a79b5d120a27ef1e" parent="aspace_ad74f72219a3b4707f9495de86d0cdb3" type="folder">1-8</container><container altrender="Manuscript box - Legal" id="aspace_a0e5145933616cc55209326cf8172cd6" label="Mixed Materials [31142063073582]" type="box">2</container><container id="aspace_95d5c8bbaf7a477a98d344e13fece650" parent="aspace_a0e5145933616cc55209326cf8172cd6" type="folder">1-9</container><container altrender="Manuscript box - Legal" id="aspace_a54ebbec1eeb55d354ee6f6a3684243f" label="Mixed Materials [31142063073590]" type="box">3</container><container id="aspace_16a57a344bb77072180038c41a6214ca" parent="aspace_a54ebbec1eeb55d354ee6f6a3684243f" type="folder">1-12</container><container altrender="Manuscript box - Legal" id="aspace_8222b31c9e05804accdbd02c2ced1fb8" label="Mixed Materials [31142063073608]" type="box">4</container><container id="aspace_5e9b2ec24af01f91022b62979626c934" parent="aspace_8222b31c9e05804accdbd02c2ced1fb8" type="folder">1-11</container><container altrender="Manuscript box - Legal" id="aspace_cf22efbb57dd15b791e053107c799293" label="Mixed Materials [31142063073616]" type="box">5</container><container id="aspace_f6eb77b9728e73c3ffd336916bb4101b" parent="aspace_cf22efbb57dd15b791e053107c799293" type="folder">1-8</container><container altrender="Manuscript box - Legal" id="aspace_fadf67eb5e79de7385678105f4636ba7" label="Mixed Materials [31142063073624]" type="box">6</container><container id="aspace_06a585ca911b0f0a73195f8aaf73b98a" parent="aspace_fadf67eb5e79de7385678105f4636ba7" type="folder">1-10</container><container altrender="Manuscript box - Legal" id="aspace_6b1f87a6bc3f8766eaea0c4d08e40f8d" label="Mixed Materials [31142063073632]" type="box">7</container><container id="aspace_7c3403ce108c074cf83d39b4e1508c7a" parent="aspace_6b1f87a6bc3f8766eaea0c4d08e40f8d" type="folder">1-8</container><container altrender="Manuscript box - Legal" id="aspace_713ffcb20892ec7340542f466624eaef" label="Mixed Materials [31142063073640]" type="box">8</container><container id="aspace_6e1b2264ddf3be119dc12f73d4870dcf" parent="aspace_713ffcb20892ec7340542f466624eaef" type="folder">1-12</container><container altrender="Manuscript box - Legal" id="aspace_2c06de5c21109c02e0c5382df159c849" label="Mixed Materials [31142063073657]" type="box">9</container><container id="aspace_75eb90168c6e0dd2834fc97d72c9e48e" parent="aspace_2c06de5c21109c02e0c5382df159c849" type="folder">1-12</container><container altrender="Flat OS Box - 16" id="aspace_00539d9dcdf899b9e9a7bdedad0360f4" label="Mixed Materials [31142062851962]" type="box">23</container><container id="aspace_de5891084884a02ec35d9e70d4a01864" parent="aspace_00539d9dcdf899b9e9a7bdedad0360f4" type="folder">8</container></did></c></c><c id="aspace_89b23f7f8c28e185647f3f347d79b54a" level="series"><did><unittitle>Series III. Articles and Clippings</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1961-1993, undated, bulk 1975-1980</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="aspace_28b47f595e4748e1dba09b38c5243f58"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>This series consists of news clippings, popular and academic articles, conference papers, press releases, leaflets and other print material. The majority of the material is related to the Indonesian occupation of East Timor and its aftermath, particularly U.S. military aid to Indonesia, the Suharto regime, Fretilin, the mass killings, famine and deprivation of East Timorese, Indonesian political prisoners and the international response. Some of the materials relate to other political and economic matters of Indonesia, Southeast Asia, and Pacific Island nations and people.  A substantial number of the articles and news clippings are photocopies. Many of the clippings are taken from major news outlets from the U.S, the UK, and Australia. Much of the press releases and other print material were created by human rights organizations, including TAPOL USA.</p></scopecontent><c id="aspace_bd9bb20221b4a82241c2e829ab20ad87" level="file"><did><unittitle>Articles and Clippings</unittitle><unitdate normal="1961/1993" type="inclusive">1961-1993</unitdate><container altrender="Manuscript box - Legal" id="aspace_03ce5d9b20f2f40795fcc8fe03b1c420" label="Mixed Materials [31142063073665]" type="box">10</container><container id="aspace_cd025ed1a5eee6c0678f75a37f2d7248" parent="aspace_03ce5d9b20f2f40795fcc8fe03b1c420" type="folder">1-10</container><container altrender="Manuscript box - Legal" id="aspace_cb776d4c31889c0ab2f42fc75b42b890" label="Mixed Materials [31142063073673]" type="box">11</container><container id="aspace_6449786319d06906696bfe2a2488550c" parent="aspace_cb776d4c31889c0ab2f42fc75b42b890" type="folder">1-7</container><container altrender="Manuscript box - Legal" id="aspace_cfc8bcd911620fcc0489242bad07577f" label="Mixed Materials [31142063073681]" type="box">12</container><container id="aspace_70605c8a51adf5f233cf8c067919d1af" parent="aspace_cfc8bcd911620fcc0489242bad07577f" type="folder">1-16</container><container altrender="Manuscript box - Legal" id="aspace_fcc3f7d2fa673c6cd8555954301d8488" label="Mixed Materials [31142063073699]" type="box">13</container><container id="aspace_d183bd7dea2a94e746b21fd4516ac937" parent="aspace_fcc3f7d2fa673c6cd8555954301d8488" type="folder">1-8</container><container altrender="Flat OS Box - 16" id="aspace_16f547ae3ee5846a278febfeb03282ae" label="Mixed Materials [31142062851962]" type="box">23</container><container id="aspace_b58f0e5875058606a329eb11c97de308" parent="aspace_16f547ae3ee5846a278febfeb03282ae" type="folder">6-7</container><container altrender="Oversize Folder - 36 x 28" id="aspace_27d1ae448542ebb57d24accdc77d78b8" label="Mixed Materials [31142063073723]" type="Flat-File-Folder">3</container></did></c></c><c id="aspace_0c6c154cfaa551159fb4abc05bc88134" level="series"><did><unittitle>Series IV. Correspondence</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1971-1985, undated
</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="aspace_88e93ded2c5bb2e7dfe21950c40c7d0d"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>This small series contains correspondence between Franke and advocates from human rights organizations, U.S. government, public interest and activist groups, policy organizations, and academics. Some of the correspondence is not directed to Franke, but amongst other parties and organizations. Several of the organizations and people represented are Amnesty International, Ford Foundation, and Committee to Protect Journalists. Much of Franke's correspondence relates to information and updates on the East Timor situation, advocacy campaigns, TAPOL funding, and requests for TAPOL and related publications. This series consists substantially of correspondence pertaining to human rights activist and TAPOL UK cofounder Carmel Budiardjo - her imprisonment, campaigns for her release, and her 1976 speaking tour in the U.S.
 
This series also contains a number of letters addressed to the U.S. Congress, the Department of State and other governmental agencies related to the situation in East Timor, Indonesian political prisoners, and U.S. aid and involvement. Some of the aforementioned letters are form letters from advocacy groups. There are also several letters to the editor of major news media outlets concerned with their coverage of the occupation of East Timor.</p></scopecontent><c id="aspace_b1640f72d7618d5f28ea619f7c70e2c6" level="file"><did><unittitle>Correspondence</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1971-1985, undated</unitdate><container altrender="Manuscript box - Legal" id="aspace_0153cdcad99418e8a695ec61304cea71" label="Mixed Materials [31142063073707]" type="box">14</container><container id="aspace_4a5dae431f381293297a4ab30131c1a8" parent="aspace_0153cdcad99418e8a695ec61304cea71" type="folder">1-19</container></did></c></c><c id="aspace_6f69a544c1e484efff1d8c9d89505a12" level="series"><did><unittitle>Series V. Franke's Writings</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1974-1982, undated
</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="aspace_e0c61b55fb149585b46a39ea74277f43"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>This small series contains Richard Franke's writings on East Timor and Indonesia. It includes some of Franke's articles and manuscripts, as well as his reviews of other works on the subject. The manuscripts include a few early drafts of Franke's pamphlet entitled "East Timor: The Hidden War," issued by the East Timor Defense Committee in 1976. It details a brief history of the Indonesian invasion of East Timor, the U.S military involvement in the conflict, Fretilin and the East Timorese' struggle for independence, and calls to action. The early drafts of this work contain inscription, including layout notes, and original photographs. There are also two copies of the final published pamphlet. Some of Franke's writings are accompanied with research material. This series also contains Franke's conference material from the Permanent People's Tribunal Session on East Timor which was held in Lisbon, Portugal on June 19-21, 1981. An oversized poster from this conference material was separated and placed in Series VII.</p></scopecontent><c id="aspace_9d8a456f84d306117d6a310503829f4f" level="file"><did><unittitle>Franke's Writings</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1974-1982, undated</unitdate><container altrender="Manuscript box - Legal" id="aspace_faa18373c9367cc491607be076cac4c4" label="Mixed Materials [31142063073715]" type="box">15</container><container id="aspace_b87384f2aac610780cc432bcc049099b" parent="aspace_faa18373c9367cc491607be076cac4c4" type="folder">1-10</container><container altrender="Flat OS Box - 16" id="aspace_d61c1555d04d186b057e5b7469231977" label="Mixed Materials [31142062851962]" type="box">23</container><container id="aspace_d3f6371c60d0d49de0b015938cc886f2" parent="aspace_d61c1555d04d186b057e5b7469231977" type="folder">9</container></did></c></c><c id="aspace_265fdeaadaecca0b9e926ea75dc5d03f" level="series"><did><unittitle>Series VI. Photographic Materials</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1975-1976, undated</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="aspace_824704e029de276ce29fc68e9e2dda2e"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>This small series consists of a few folders of photographic material, including black and white photographs and some negatives. There are photographs and negatives of a TAPOL protest to be used in their newsletters, a photograph and negative of a Fretilin meeting, and a few photographs of Carmel Budiardjo, TAPOL UK co-founder and former Indonesian political prisoner. Additional photographs can be found in Series V. within Franke's manuscript draft.</p></scopecontent><c id="aspace_bfb97ab9d5903ec9b8a8d5bce71c2494" level="file"><did><unittitle>Carmel Budiardjo of Tapol - photographs</unittitle><unitdate>undated</unitdate><container altrender="Manuscript box - Legal" id="aspace_6ce97b4a2046d081439d6b5bbd0ddb78" label="photographs [31142063073574]" type="box">1</container><container id="aspace_1aa04f1549cffe631aec0a002b7c0b31" parent="aspace_6ce97b4a2046d081439d6b5bbd0ddb78" type="folder">9</container></did></c><c id="aspace_411cb03638fdf704da480e27a2bda4b6" level="file"><did><unittitle>Timor Meeting - photograph and negative</unittitle><unitdate normal="1976-04-10/1976-04-10">1976-04-10</unitdate><container altrender="Manuscript box - Legal" id="aspace_2e6cce26133429d94728af5ca323e31d" label="photographs [31142063073624]" type="box">6</container><container id="aspace_809688634adb73f367004cc5655c7f46" parent="aspace_2e6cce26133429d94728af5ca323e31d" type="folder">4</container></did></c><c id="aspace_bf46bbb072e06f13097e5d0223c2d390" level="file"><did><unittitle>East Timor Famine - photographs</unittitle><unitdate>undated</unitdate><container altrender="Manuscript box - Legal" id="aspace_18e78b96e3bb096ade7f9aeb26861952" label="photographs [31142063073640]" type="box">8</container><container id="aspace_a82614742bd451edae3f42831c234be8" parent="aspace_18e78b96e3bb096ade7f9aeb26861952" type="folder">3</container></did></c><c id="aspace_6be2e07b863ac83a20c6e989a1c03110" level="file"><did><unittitle>Tapol - photographs and negatives</unittitle><unitdate>1975, undated</unitdate><container altrender="Manuscript box - Legal" id="aspace_69f2fd70d12c6da4c1fd8e295839b028" label="photographs [31142063073699]" type="box">13</container><container id="aspace_b5526900a250108adf37e6f225dc7a5b" parent="aspace_69f2fd70d12c6da4c1fd8e295839b028" type="folder">9</container></did></c></c><c id="aspace_c78c1e52dcd5e4b7ff1ddbee0e67fa63" level="series"><did><unittitle>Series VII. Graphic Materials and Memorabilia</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1975-1980, undated</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="aspace_c68039c5d18f1b98c08d37b622f73c73"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>This series contains several posters created by various human rights and advocacy organizations. The posters pertain to human rights campaigns and calls to action on East Timor and Indonesian political prisoners. Such organizations include PEN International, and the British Campaign for an Independent East Timor. Some of the posters are related to U.S. and international events and conferences on East Timor, including the Permanent Peoples' Tribunal on East Timor in Lisbon. This series also contains a small grouping of Fretilin stickers and TAPOL buttons.</p></scopecontent><c id="aspace_174d3f0929828cef9dc33432ae3238f2" level="file"><did><unittitle>Fretilin - stickers</unittitle><unitdate>undated </unitdate><container altrender="Manuscript box - Legal" id="aspace_22c18ef18a5a70d795b5cb6b76866ecf" label="Mixed Materials [31142063073707]" type="box">14</container><container id="aspace_fd9ccced13fe93a3db3c611bb1b2010c" parent="aspace_22c18ef18a5a70d795b5cb6b76866ecf" type="folder">20</container></did></c><c id="aspace_43ccd11e41ccc861173debea6c5d3156" level="file"><did><unittitle>Tapol - buttons </unittitle><unitdate>undated</unitdate><container altrender="Manuscript box - Legal" id="aspace_c09411e46c1d47d70b7cfc4665528942" label="Mixed Materials [31142063073715]" type="box">15</container></did></c><c id="aspace_5f72478930412c34b0fb2850a46782f6" level="file"><did><unittitle>Posters</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1975-1980, undated</unitdate><container altrender="Oversize Folder - 36 x 28" id="aspace_15814a24359a06fccbf8e800fb511a4f" label="Graphic Materials [31142063073723]" type="Flat-File-Folder">3</container></did></c></c><c id="aspace_9950d50d149192a3a11be8a57b25c492" level="series"><did><unittitle>Series VIII. Audiovisual Materials</unittitle><unitdate normal="1976/1980" type="inclusive">1976-1980</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="aspace_2ec710b0994a6e153b2b4e011e8138fe"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>This series consists of a 16 mm color film entitled "East Timor: Isle of Fear, Isle of Hope." The 20-minute documentary film was produced by Algerian filmmaker Adjili and distributed by the East Timor Defense Committee, circa 1976. The film is about East Timor's independence struggle under both the Portuguese colonial rule and the subsequent Indonesia occupation.  This series also contains an audiocassette entitled "Independencia Total: Revolutionary Songs of East Timor and Indonesia," jointly produced by Fretilin and Agin Timur, circa 1980.</p></scopecontent><c id="aspace_b43e7f487d227aba3630536a23aa12c5" level="file"><did><unittitle>"East Timor: Isle of Fear, Isle of Hope"</unittitle><unitdate normal="1976/1976">1976</unitdate><container altrender="OS Flat Box - 15x19x3" id="aspace_de586b1a5ffc55cf7a42f4c1243d1374" label="film reels (16mm) [31142062725455]" type="box">24</container></did></c><c id="aspace_204495dc10f2d72f228fbb229144a817" level="file"><did><unittitle>"Independencia Total: Revolutionary Songs of East Timor and Indonesia"</unittitle><unitdate normal="1980/1980">1980</unitdate><container altrender="Hollinger Cassette Box 5" id="aspace_55bb8bf97da2fb9fa799f07798db4243" label="Audio [31142063133824]" type="box">Shared Cassette Box 18</container></did></c></c></dsc>
</archdesc>
</ead>
